Right, team. Welcome back to the
channel. My name's Tom Youngs.
This is the whiteboard of truth. And in
today's video, I need you to forget
everything that you think you know about
closing high ticket. Because what we're
talking about today are the one, two,
three key sales assets that have allowed
me to do what I call the zero cool
close. Because in 2024, when I was
making about 100 grand in the year, I
was doing sales calls. And in fact, my
calendar, in one week I had went and
counted them, had 17 calls in a single
week. And it had five on a Friday
afternoon. The cool thing is, I was
like, "I'm done with this." It's October
2024. I quit sales calls. And since
then, I've now done 1.6 million in my
consulting business without a single
call, zero sales calls, zero appointment
setters, zero sales closes. And it
typically takes me less than 30 minutes
per day to manage my entire pipeline. I
think that's sick. So, if you stick
around for this video, I'm going to talk
to you about the one, two, three sales
assets that are going to help you get
there, too. If that's what you want. If
that is what you want. Like I said,
welcome. My name's Tom, if you're new
here. I have a gift for you, as always,
to the newbs.
There is a link down below that's going
to take you to a free mini course that
is going to, over the next 7 days, send
you a single email to your inbox. I call
it six to seven figures in 7 days. It's
going to be a 3-minute daily read.
Everything that I've done to go and
navigate this journey over the last
couple of years, so you can do it, too.
Okay, let's crack a fresh bottle of
South Downs natural mineral sparkling
water.
Our sponsor for today, they don't know
it, but
I send them a lot of business. Okay,
let's get into this.
Right, so we're talking about three key
assets. One, the model. Two, the
machine. Three, the invite.
What does this all mean? This all starts
from a common mistake most online
experts make.
This is a pyramid called the levels of
awareness.
This is a sequence of awareness steps
that a prospect needs to go through to
be able to go from not having a clue
what you do to understanding exactly
what you do and eventually
sending you the seven most lucrative
words in business, which is "Can you
send me the payment link?" Can you send
me the payment link? Boom, that's what
we want. Because on honestly most online
experts get hit with the seven most
expensive words in online business or
just in business in general, which is "I
just need to think about it." And I
don't want that to be you.
I want you to be able to close deals
without all the [__] that everyone
else has to go through. So, like I said,
this is all about moving people through
the levels of awareness. This is from a
book by Eugene Schwartz called a
Breakthrough Advertising. Very expensive
OG book, but one I would highly
recommend reading.
Uh so, how this works.
When someone is in your audience and
they follow you, but they
don't have a clue who you are, don't
have a clue what you do, don't have a
clue how you help people. In fact, they
are even unaware that they even have a
problem themselves. So, our job when we
grow our social media audiences is to at
first tell people that they actually
have a problem. And what that does is
that moves people from being unaware
down to being problem aware. Now, our
public content does that job. Videos
like this on YouTube, videos like my
reels on Instagram. Shout out, I just
hit 100K on Instagram.
Let's go. So, um that's pretty sick. Um
so, um
that's what our content to our audience
is about. It's about getting people
right at the top of the levels of
awareness to actually be aware that they
have a problem. So, that's phase one.
But, we're not talking about phase one
today. I've made plenty of videos
talking about that phase.
You can just go binge the rest of my
channel, okay? If you don't believe me,
but this is what we need to do next.
The next stage of this is when someone
knows that they have a problem.
So, so someone knows they have the
problem.
Let me start this again.
Come on, Tom. You can do this.
It's not like it's your first time.
We then need to take someone from being
problem aware to solution aware.
We need to essentially shift a belief
that there is a better way of them to do
things, okay? That's the second thing we
need to do. The third thing we need to
do is we need to move them being from
solution aware.
Come on, Tom. You can do this.
We need to take them from being solution
aware to being product aware. That is
they are aware they have a problem. They
are aware that there is a solution for
them to help solve their problem. And
then, they are finally aware that there
is a product that exists in the
marketplace, your product.
Or a product. Potentially not just your
product.
Um could be someone else's product as
well that helps them solve their
solution. You need to take them to being
product aware. And then finally, finally
once you've done all of those steps, you
need to take someone to the point in
which they are most aware. And when they
are most aware, they are most aware that
you [snorts]
have the solution for them.
Now, the problem is most online experts
most online experts make the [__]
mistake of trying to do this. Boom.
They try and get people from being
unaware
to most aware in one step. And that's an
issue.
Because
why would someone who isn't even aware
that they have a problem be interested
in your product?
Makes no sense. So, we are not going to
be doing this, okay?
Now, this fundamentally comes down to
this misunderstanding of the question
that is going on in people's heads at
each stage.
Now, what most experts think is that
when someone's watching their content,
they're thinking, "Hmm.
I wonder how his [__] works."
But that's not what they're thinking.
What they are actually thinking, and
which what is the answer that we have to
help them solve,
or what at least we need to help them
solve this answer this question in their
head,
it's this.
Why is what I'm doing
not working? That's the question we need
to solve.
Our like perfect future clients,
the question that we need to solve
Tom can't think today.
Tom can't speak today, in fact.
Come on. Let's pull this [__] together,
man. You've got this.
The question that people try and solve
is I wonder how his [__] works.
And that is not the question that's
going on in their head. The question
that's going on in their heads are why
is what I'm doing not working? So, this
system that we're going to talk about
today, the three-step system that I've
been refining and perfecting over the
last two and a half years, or two years
actually,
um
is based all around this.
It starts over here with the first asset
called the model, okay? So, um I've been
to a number of networking events over
the last couple of years, and I've been
to two where one of the goats out there,
one of the modern goats, Sabri Suby, um
Australian geezer, uh he runs an agency
called King Kong. Um and
he has spent a lot of money on ads. And
uh I've seen him twice, and both times
he's like, "The perfect length of this
type of video is 27 minutes." So, this
is typically what people will call a
video sales letter, but most people get
it wrong. Most experts get this wrong
because what they are trying to do is
they're trying to go down at this end of
the spectrum when they need to be going
up, okay?
So, this video is all about taking
people from being problem aware to
solution aware, okay?
And this is the difference between
making a video which in the video you
talk about the offer first, which is
here's what you get, the modules, the
features, the coaching, the community,
the time with you, the the one-on-one
access, you know, all the [__]
that someone who's this high up, they
don't care about. It's not what you need
to be talking to them about. What you
need to be talking to them about
is
"Here's why you've been playing the
wrong game."
This is what the whole point of this
video is there to do, okay? The whole
point of this video is to tell them and
shift their belief that they are
currently playing a game that is wrong,
and that you have a new game for them to
play that is the correct way to do
things, and a better way for them to get
the result they're actually looking for,
okay?
So, the whole point of this video is
that the model changes what they
believe, okay? So, I'll give you an
example of this, right? If you're
If you're new here, um my big
overarching thesis for how I build
seven-figure brands online for experts
is that I used to be a funnel analytics
consultant for really big enterprise
brands. So,
uh
fashion brands like Tommy Hilfiger,
Selfridges, Harrods, Superdry, Sweaty
Betty, uh banks like TSB, NatWest used
to be my clients. So, I used to work on
um Virgin Atlantic, Virgin Holidays.
Uh I used to be the the brands that I
used to look at their data. I used to
look at their Google Analytics, their
user analytics. I used to literally look
underneath the hood of their businesses,
see all their numbers. And I my job was
to work with their teams to highlight
where there were gaps in their funnels.
Now, what I realized a few years ago was
that some of the biggest experts in the
world, the guys like
the Gadzhievs,
the Abdallahs, the Cods, all of those
guys, this is a few years ago. I was
like, "These guys aren't using funnels
like how I used to help big brands
make their funnels better."
It became obvious to me that they were
doing something really different.
And so, 3 years ago, I came up with this
new model of building an online expert
brand, which I now call the one simple
flywheel.
Instead of people
like
basically driving traffic to a sales
page and just being like hoping that
they click the buy button,
instead, what we have is we've got a
series of four systems that we take
someone from being a follower, so
someone who just follows you online, to
becoming a lead, someone that you can
contact. That's the first system. The
second system, which most online experts
are missing, is then an education
system. And that takes people from being
someone who's a lead just to being an
actual paying customer.
Once they've become a customer, we then
have a system to turn them into being a
high-paying client. And then the final
system, arguably the most important
system of the entire one simple flywheel
model is you turn them into a case
study. You actually help them get the
result that you promise you can get
them.
And so
this way of doing things
as I've built over the last couple of
years
builds a brand. Whereas funnels are
essentially tactics that rely on they're
like fashion trends. And so you can't
rely on fashion trends because guess
what?
They go out of trend.
It's not working.
But this is when you build a brand based
on fundamentals, based on brand
fundamentals
it's evergreen. You don't have to worry
about the fashion trends. So my model is
all about helping people understand that
there is the old way of doing things
back when ads were really dirt cheap,
you know, back in the ClickFunnels days,
back in the Jim Roach days. That was
when Alex Hormozi built Jim Roach, I'm
sure you know who he is.
Let's talk about the goat, Russell
Brunson, talking about the ClickFunnels
days.
Um
when ads were really cheap, back in the
arbitrage days of early Facebook ads,
you could buy leads for dirt cheap and
you could afford to push a loads of
people through funnels and just a you
could it was just cheap. But now when
there's more creators, there's more
brands than ever, there's more
businesses than ever, there is um a
noisier marketplace
you have to rely on a more evergreen
model than just relying on the fashion
trends. And I see this all the time with
online experts who, you know, they they
make these videos all I burnt down my
coaching business.
You know. I burnt I literally saw
another one today where another another
guy's literally started his again cuz he
burnt it out a bunch of months ago and
he's like, "Yeah, well, um I tried
something else and that also didn't go
honestly
uh
it's because they're relying on fashion
trends, not building an actual brand. So
um
I want you to remember this. So this is
a write-it-downer.
You don't sell the offer, you sell the
shift. That is what this core asset is
all about. It's about selling the shift
only. Now, I have a framework for this
called the 11 P's. This is what I work
with inside Scale 20, which is my
consulting and advisory firm for
six-figure experts to help them scale to
seven figures. And over the past 3
years,
these videos that I've made public on my
YouTube channel. So, I have an other
another YouTube channel, by the way. I
would highly recommend going and
subscribing to that. I post That's where
we kind of break down all of our
our case studies that I help crush. Um
those videos that I've used the 11 P's
framework for
have been not only my best-performing
videos publicly on my channel,
they have consistently been some of the
best-performing videos in the entire
online business market. Like, I [__] you
not. Uh hundreds of thousands of views
publicly on my channel because I have
created a framework that truly works for
this. And it's kind of the proof is
really in the pudding there because
by virtue of the fact that it is
shifting beliefs, it is getting more
views because it's something that people
can see. They know that they need to
stop using funnels.
And so, I've been using this model, this
framework, the 11 P's. I call it my one
simple video. And this is the the main
asset that gets people to believe there
is a new way of doing things, okay? Now,
if you want to see an example of that,
I've got you, but you're going to have
to wait right till the end of the next
video, okay?
Bloody hell, I really can't speak today.
You're going to have to wait till the
end of this video, okay? Then we're
going to I'm going to literally going to
be like, "Hey, go watch this video. You
will see an example of this." Right.
Number two is the machine.
This is a 30-minute to 1-hour
unlisted video, okay? Now, don't go and
do this yet,
but if you look down below, down in the
description box, the first line in the
description box is this video, okay?
Don't click it yet. I'll tell you when
to click it. Actually, you know what?
Don't click it yet because wait till the
end of this video. You need to watch the
model video first, then you watch this
video. If you don't watch in sequence,
it's not going to make sense for you,
okay? You're not going to see how this
whole system ties together. But, the
point is this video is linked to the top
of every single one of my description
boxes on all my YouTube videos, okay?
But, it is unlisted. It's not publicly
available on my channel, okay?
The whole point of this video is to move
people from being solution aware to
product aware. You can see we're getting
further down here. So, the model was up
here. The model was talking about how
you how the how you do things
differently to how the how the rest of
the market does things.
The second video, the machine, is the
actual
nuts and bolts, or as you can actually
you might not be able to see cuz of the
light. I know my key light I've people
send me messages occasionally.
I am in a small office in London in an
apartment, okay? There is absolutely no
other [__] place I can put this key
light so that it illuminates both me and
to some extent the whiteboard, all
right? So, you're going to have to just
promise me. You might be able to see
this, but
I said the nuts and bolts, or
another element of a machine, you might
say, is a cog. How do you like my little
illustration of a cog?
Yeah? Pretty damn good, right? You might
not be able to see it, but there's a
really shitty illustration of a cog up
there. Anyway,
that is the idea. We have the model
that's talking about how this works,
um or sorry, why this works, and then
the machine is talking about how it
works. Right.
Super super important idea here.
High ticket
is a considered
purchase, okay?
High ticket is a considered purchase.
Now, what that means is that the buying
journey from someone going from problem
aware to most aware
is different than an impulse purchase.
Like, for example,
I needed some new creatine the other
day. So, I just went to Amazon, I typed
in creatine, and I bought the top one
that was there. I think it was even a
sponsored post. I didn't think about it.
I had bought it within 3 seconds, okay?
Um
you don't do that
with high ticket. When there's um
multiple months involved, there's work
that's going to get be involved, there's
all the stuff that goes along with
selling like high ticket coaching and
consulting. It's a considered purchase.
So,
imagine this.
Imagine you walk into a Rolex shop. Now,
I'm not a fan of Rolexes, not my
favorite watch brand.
I don't intend to ever have one, but
you get the point. A Rolex, okay?
You go into the Rolex shop.
You walk around.
You have a little look around. You're
like, "Ooh, I like that one. Yeah,
that's a nice That's a nice That's a
nice watch." You want to actually put
some on your wrist. Okay?
What happens next? You go to the dude
and you say, "Hey, I like the look of
this bad boy over here, okay? I think it
would look sick on my wrist, but I need
to I need to validate that it would look
sick on my wrist.
I've got small wrists, okay?
I'm a thin-boned human.
And so, I need to make sure that this
Rolex doesn't overcrowd
my petite wrist structure,
okay?
So,
what the dude does is he says, "Of
course, sir.
Follow me
into this
private room
where
we'll get that Rolex on on wrist."
So, you go through to this private
inspection room
and he sits you down. He asks, "Would
you like a glass of water?"
Everything's nice and calm.
Closes the door behind you. And then he
brings a selection of three Rolexes out.
Interestingly,
the one he the one you asked for
and a couple of others that he thinks
might look good on your wrist, okay?
And also, if you know anything about
Rolex, uh those are the ones he's
actually going to sell you because you
won't be able to get the one that you
want.
Besides the point. Okay.
You're in the private inspection room.
You have a conversation, you try on all
the watches, and he says, "Hey, by the
way,
I I can't give you this
watch this Rolex because there's a
waitlist for it.
But, these this one or this one
absolutely, we can you can walk out
today with this Rolex."
And um
this has been on your mind for a while.
You've been wanting to get a
a watch for a for a while. You wanted to
treat yourself. And you knew walking
into this shop what was going to happen.
You knew this was going to happen
because it was a considered purchase,
okay? You'd been considering it for a
while.
You were aware that
there was a problem.
You couldn't tell the time. You knew
that there was solution out there, a
watch. You then knew there were
different products out there. There was
the Apple Watch. There was also
Omegas. There was
I don't know. Swatch. There's also
Rolexes.
You're not quite at the Patek level yet.
So, you know that, right?
And so, you're then product aware. And
then finally, you're like, "You know
what? I really want the Rolex." So,
you're at this stage and you walk into
the shop. You know this is going to
happen, okay?
So,
you've had an opportunity to inspect the
product.
You've You've worn the product. You've
demoed it. You know exactly what you
get. You know how much it costs.
You know exactly You know today you can
walk out with it.
So, you've walked in
and
this is if you can imagine yourself as
an online expert, what we're trying to
do here is we're trying to give a
private inspection room, a video that is
operating like that private inspection
room, okay?
And
if you do this correctly, what happens
is you then also you sell the vehicle,
okay? And I need to change this here
because this is wrong. This is the
machine.
So, the machine sells the vehicle.
The model
sells the shift, okay?
Now, the important thing is when you do
these videos, you have to
also make sure that you
take people through the shift again at
the start of this video in the machine.
You need to remind people that there is
a better way of doing things. But then
this is the opportunity for you to
actually talk about, "Okay, there's this
problem that you have. There's a
solution that you know would work for
you. We also have a product that's going
to help you then. It's the same for me."
And like I said, if you click down at
the bottom down there, if you are a
six-figure online expert
and you'd like to scale to your first or
next 20k monthly goal all the way to
seven figures, which is what we do,
then you can click the link and you can
watch that video and see how I do it
inside Scale 101 and how we do it very
differently to other people out there,
okay?
Um
once you do this,
you then get the opportunity to invite
people.
But here's the key thing.
We are going to be inviting
the right person.
So, the beauty of this one-two-three
part sales asset structure
is that at every single point, you are
filtering out the wrong people.
So, at every stage you get closer and
closer and closer to filtering in your
perfect future client, okay? So, what we
do here, imagine like, you know, it's
The Great Gatsby, right? You know, he's
the dude, Leo. He's got that cheers gif.
Everyone wants to be invited, okay? No
one wants to be sold. No one wants to be
convinced. Everyone wants to be invited,
okay? And so, what this is about is
simply having all of the details of how
your thing works on a simple page or a
document. Now, people in the market are
talking about how oh, you can just use
it on a just sell it on a Google Doc.
That's all you need. You just need a
simple doc to tell them in short.
Absolutely. Do your thing. Do your
thing.
All I'm saying is that it doesn't
[__] matter, okay?
At the end of the day, it's just you
need to send someone to a place where
the details of how
it actually works working with you is
all in one place.
So, for me, we have it in a simple
document. Um but, for people to get it,
they have to have gone through these
stages to eventually get the call to
action to get given the invite, which is
to DM me 77 on Instagram. Now, when they
DM me 77 on Instagram, it triggers uh a
specific inbound ManyChat automation,
which serves them
this video and the invite and collects
their contact details so I know who they
are. So, it does three things in one go.
So, the invite is all about doing these
three things.
It's about highlighting who it's not
for. So, really important, I
out the gate, I'm like, this is who it's
not for. If this is you,
if you're reading these lines and this
is you, then this is not for you. For
example, I don't work with beginners
right now, okay? I only work with people
who have traction, who have actually got
an offer that the helps people get an
amazing result. I don't work with people
with personal development offers, so
fitness coaches, life coaches. I just
I've never run one of those businesses.
So, I only help people who essentially
are business coaches, business
consultants, people who help people make
more money, okay? And that's how I'm
able to specialize so deeply and help my
members and clients get absolutely mega
results because I'm super specific.
There are so many coaches and and
consultants out there who are [__]
like work with everyone.
And it's like you really think that you
can be a specialist in everything?
Absolutely [__] Like fundamentally
this is just an aside. Like say for
example like a fitness coaching business
fundamentally is about accountability
and support.
Um and education and a training business
or consulting business is about
education, mastery, and giving them a
clear roadmap, okay? Completely
different.
So, how could I do that? Okay, anyway.
Um if you do these three things,
the model sells the belief shift,
the machine sells the vehicle,
and then the invite invites the right
person.
And those are the three sales assets
that have allowed me to scale to 1.6
million
over the past 20 months since dropping
sales calls completely.
And I think that's sick.
Like I promised you halfway through this
video, if you would like to see
an a banger example of the model,
then I'm going to get you to watch this
video next, okay?
That was sick.
And I'll see you in the next one.